[Music]
hi and welcome to this session on Cross
environment consulation my name is Brian
Nelson I'm a program manager in the
business Central team we're going to
show a new feature that is expanding the
uh consolidation feature or sub feature
to the consolidation feature what we
will do in this session is a brief recap
of of consolidation I'll show you the
how it's done um in a normal case uh
then we will show you how it's done in
with the new feature where you are doing
cross environment consolidation looks
the same but it is different and then
Joshua will take you through how you set
it up um there's a a bit of work and not
much and lastly uh Joshua will give you
some tips and tricks but let's uh look
at what is
consolidation consolidation is when you
need to uh import or consolidate your
financial statements from multiple uh
business entities if you're group of
businesses to get a complete overview of
the group um we call them business units
the subsidiary or sales offices or any
other legal entity that you have we can
support multicurrency so the
subsidiaries don't have to have the same
currency as the parent or holding
company that you're consolidating into
there is a feature so that you can map
the chart of accounts they don't have to
be the same you'll just do the mapping
in the subsidiary to the consolidation
company's chart of
accounts and we also handle minority
interest but let's just take a brief
look at at how the feat feat looks
like so in this company you can see that
in my environment and this is the same
environment I have two like I have
actually a lot more companies I have my
holding company and I have two other
companies Brian's beans and Joshua's
coffee these are my two subsidiaries to
the holding company I've set them up as
business
units and for these I have done some
specific applications I specify what the
name is uh what currency rate I want to
use it can be the subsidiaries or the
holding companies and you can choose to
use the currency exchange rate or the
currency exchange rate for the
additional reporing currency you can
also Define how much you want to
consolidate and if you don't consolidate
100% so you have minority interest we'll
still do the consolidation but then um
also post when you do the consolation
will post the offsetting entries for the
minority interest and then there are
accounts to handle the gains and losses
if you are doing uh a subsidiary in
currencies the bottom part we'll get to
that uh in a second so I've set up these
companies uh I've done some uh importing
and what you can do is uh you can run a
trial balance for consolidation you can
also set up because it's business units
you can do financial
reporting and I've created a report here
called consolidation
per business unit and you'll be able to
see if I scroll down a bit that I have
my Incorporated the holding company I
have beans and coffee and then I have
something
extra uh and I have numbers for at least
the beans because that's the one I've
imported so far but you can uh you can
import your businesses and then through
financial reporting or an external bi
tool you can get a a an overview of your
combined business
so up until now it worked with within
environment companies so these two that
are in the same environment I could just
hit the consolidate button and it would
import the data from these companies if
the company recited somewhere else in
the world different region different
environment I would have to use files to
Import and Export uh my consolidation
information but we have changed it for
this session as Joshua will show uh you
set up a company that is in a different
environment so let's have a look at how
we can import data from a different
environment so here I am in my holding
company and here I have only a us uh
subsidiary and I want to import data
from the US subsidiary and also from a
British subsidiary Kronos GBP
bins so let's see in the holding company
you can go to the business units page
here I have them already set up and and
I can click the action
consolidate and I can set up the
starting date the ending date for this
consolidation document number with which
you want to identify the entries that
get posted in this company and yeah this
gets prefilled with the currency that
this uh company has in this case it's
USD so when you want to run the
consolidation you are presented with a
list of the business units that you have
in case you need to to authenticate
because you haven't run consolidations
recently you have to select this and it
will prompt you to uh click this grant
access action that will prompt the an
authentication flow and see that you
actually have access to that company in
this case we have access so we can just
go ahead and say
finish now the consolidation is
successful and we can see these entries
in this company so now that we have uh
performed the consolidation let's see
and have a look at the datas that were
exported from the other company so here
in our holding company I can go to
financial
reports and here I have the same
financial report Brian
showed and here I have the different
accounts and I have a total uh what's in
each of the business
units
yeah for for the consolidation period
that we
selected so let's have a look at how we
can set up some uh the business units
for cross environment so we go to the
business units page and just as before
we can add a new business
unit here we will add the British uh
beans company that we have and the main
difference on how you set up this uh is
that now you can set up an API type
here uh when you do this then you can
consolidate across environment it
doesn't necessarily need to be in this
same environment so and it requ requires
an API endpoint so how can you get this
endpoint you can get this through the
page consolidation setup in the other
company so here it is my uh subsidiary
company so if we go to the page
consolidation
setup we you will see an environment uh
endpoint we can copy
this and then we can paste it
here after this you will be required to
authenticate in that company so in this
page you have to authenticate with the
user in the other
company and after this is done you are
required to select which company in this
environment you want to set up so it's
this one
and that's it uh you have now a new uh
business unit that can communicate with
it yeah something important to note also
is that before doing this consolidation
setup you have to enable this company a
subsidiary so when you toggle this you
can import data if you at any time don't
want data to be extracted from this
company you can disable
this yes perfect so now you can
consolidate uh companies that are either
in the same environment or in a
completely different
environment um if you then do the
mapping for currencies or for the chart
of accounts uh it should be a smooth
process from now
on um Joshua you may have some tips and
tricks yeah so just as a general uh
overview of what happened this new
consolidate action and that has this
wizard you may have been familiar with
the report that we had before the report
still still exists and won't be
deprecated so you can still use it uh
and we use it for the database so the
the procedures for running the
consolidation are internal uh so we
don't expose them right now but you can
run this wizard from your Al
code and yeah that's just it just a just
a small thing nice to know yeah thank
you uh we hope you like the feature and
we'll start using it for your
consolidation going forward
thanks for joining this
session